Suyash Deshmukh

San Jose, CA | (562) 850-7043

suyash.deshmukh22@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/suyashdeshmukh https://suyashdeshmukh.github.io

Summary

Passionate frontend developer with expertise in JavaScript and related frameworks like Angular and React. Enthusiastic about new UI development technologies and frameworks to build responsive web designs.

Technical Skills

Frameworks: React, Angular, Polymer, Node js, Express, Laravel

Programming: JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Java, PHP, Functional Programming. **Web:** HTML5, CSS3, Less, Sass, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Flexbox, CSS Grid

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server, Oracle 11g

Other: git, npm, webpack, cordova, AWS, REST

Professional Experience

Web Developer, Associated Students Inc., California State University Long Beach

June 2017 – May 2018

- Developed application as SPA using Angular 5, Angular Material, and Angular UI, Material cards and used Flexbox.
- Used Ajax for asynchronously exchanging small amount of JSON data with the server behind the scenes.
- Performed cross browser testing and coding for making pages compatible will all browsers.

Software Engineer, Mphasis, Bangalore, India

June 2014 - July 2016

- Involved in SDLC Requirements gathering, Analysis, Design, Development and Testing of application developed using agile methodology
- Developed and maintained Java based integration services for renowned financial institution.
- Collaborated with a team to develop and enhance automation testing framework for wealth management organization.

Education

California State University Long Beach, USA

Fall 2016 - Spring 2018

Master of Science, Computer Science

University of Pune, India

Fall 2010 - Spring 2014

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

Projects (github.com/SuyashDeshmukh)

ASI Active (asicsulb.org/active) (Angular 4, Ionic, Typescript, Less)

- Developed a multiplatform wellness application for student employees of Associated Students Inc.
- Enhanced the wellness awareness across the campus by 40% with this application.
- Developed of QR code scanner and score service module to extend the functionality for events.

Helping hands (Angular 4, Bootstrap, Socket.io, WebSockets Express, Node.js)

- Developed a web application to allow strangers to communicate and vent out.
- Led the frontend development to collaborate with complex backend logic.

22 West Media (22westmedia.com) (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ¡Query, PHP, Joomla)

- Developed a media hub website for radio, video and magazine departments under ASI.
- Worked with content management systems for content heavy sections of the application.
- Handled complex template overriding and radio module development by collaborating with external APIs.

Reporting System (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Material Design)

- Built an internal reporting system application for ASI government.
- Developed frontend with Material design UI and vanilla JavaScript implemented with ES6 features.

Secure Chat Application (PHP, Laravel, JWT, PGP, LAMP)

- Developed an end to end secure chat application to provide secure communication channel to the users.
- Involved in the REST API development using PHP, Laravel with authentication process handled by JWT.

Twitter Content App (Angular 6, Express, Node.js)

• Developed an application to fetch and sort tweets based on hashtags, count and category filters.